<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Charged</title>
    <description>The best tech news distilled</description>
    <link>http://char.gd</link>
    
      
        <item>
          <title>The reason I keep going back to Apple might surprise you</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the last few months I&amp;rsquo;ve complained a lot about what Apple is doing – some of the moves it&amp;rsquo;s making have been frustrating, like dropping the headphone jack, the lack of any progress on OS X and in general how poor iCloud is. The media loves to portray Apple as always right, but as a customer, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t always feel that way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started considering switching from the iPhone and Apple Watch to something else, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theverge.com/2016/10/7/13207382/google-pixel-xl-camera-photography-samples&quot;&gt;like Google&amp;rsquo;s interesting new Pixel phone&lt;/a&gt;, especially with that amazing camera. But today, I had a realization about why I stick with Apple&amp;rsquo;s products: the customer experience really is a class above everyone else in the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had an iPhone 6s essentially since it came out, but recently it started developing some strange issues. First, the loudspeaker became distorted so you couldn&amp;rsquo;t clearly hear anything at all. Annoying, but not the end of the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, after iOS 10 came out, I noticed my battery life went off a cliff. Not slightly-less-but-managable, but instead needing to hang off a charger because I&amp;rsquo;d lose 25% just opening Slack for a few minutes. It was pretty bad, and I blamed software at first, but realized something else might be going wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I booked a Genius appointment, like I have many times before, to see if something was really wrong. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the appointment, I described the problem and we ran through a series of diagnostics on the phone automatically. It was, conclusively, screwed – the speaker alone warranted an entire replacement, but the battery issues were caused by a logic board problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple replaced it on the spot. No questions, accusation, argument or begging, I just got a new phone five minutes after walking in. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/proof.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s amazing how this experience flies in the face of every other type of customer service interaction we&amp;rsquo;re used to. Usually, when something goes wrong your default setting is to go in expecting a fight, or at least resistance to your problem. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously, it&amp;rsquo;s probably your fault, and retailers love to point that out. If they finally admit fault, they&amp;rsquo;ll usually send it off for repairs rather than actually just give you a new one or fix it on the spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In that world, Apple is starkly the opposite. Something&amp;rsquo;s wrong? Great, here&amp;rsquo;s a better phone for free. Broken screen? Perfect, it&amp;rsquo;ll be fixed within an hour for a nominal fee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The entire Genius system is so good, that I realized this level of service is the major reason I&amp;rsquo;m still buying Apple products: I know if something goes wrong with my MacBook, iPhone or Watch, that I&amp;rsquo;ll be taken care of, and nobody&amp;rsquo;s going to accuse me of doing something wrong or make me suffer because of the issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had this experience consistently with Apple&amp;rsquo;s customer care, who are happy to just help you get going again, rather than run you around, and it&amp;rsquo;s refreshing. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No other phone maker, carrier or even laptop maker does this, and it&amp;rsquo;s easy to forget that while we&amp;rsquo;re distracted about whether or not the iPhone 7 is the best phone ever – I just don&amp;rsquo;t care anymore, as long as I know I can actually get help when I need it. With the Pixel, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.androidpolice.com/2016/10/04/googles-247-live-support-for-the-pixel-phones-comes-complete-with-screen-sharing/&quot;&gt;Google seems to be trying&lt;/a&gt;, but time will tell whether that actually matters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, your reaction to this post might be &amp;ldquo;oh, but Apple&amp;rsquo;s products are overpriced&amp;rdquo; but when I&amp;rsquo;ve factored in that I&amp;rsquo;ve received four full phone replacements over the years as well as a Mac replacement, no questions asked, it&amp;rsquo;s worth every dollar. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That peace of mind, and great service, is worth whatever premium you might think is attached to the company&amp;rsquo;s products. Being treated like a human, rather than just another complaining asshole, is refreshing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of Apple&amp;rsquo;s product decisions are frustrating, yes, but I&amp;rsquo;ll be a loyal customer long-term, provided Apple&amp;rsquo;s stores and support systems continue to exist. Nobody else can offer that level of service, nor have they come close thus far. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>2016-10-04T00:00:00+02:00</pubDate>
          <link>http://char.gd/iphone/the-reason-i-keep-going-back-to-apple/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">http://char.gd/iphone/the-reason-i-keep-going-back-to-apple/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Google's software is putting Apple to shame</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;The narrative of Apple vs Google has always been a persistent one: Apple is great at hardware and software that fits together perfectly, and Google was never particularly good at either of those.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, Google held a &amp;ldquo;Pixel&amp;rdquo; event to unveil its new self-designed and self-built hardware: a phone, a router and, most intriguingly, a home assistant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The home assistant, &lt;a href=&quot;https://madeby.google.com/home/&quot;&gt;aptly named &amp;lsquo;Google Home&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a&gt; is a small speaker that lives in your house and can respond – from basically anywhere – to any question you might have for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/ghome.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That new speaker is powered by a piece of software called Google Assistant. It&amp;rsquo;s the company&amp;rsquo;s first push into what it calls &amp;#39;personalized search&amp;rsquo; – or a Google that knows about you intimately and can help based on the context it has from your email, search habits or any other data it has access to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://assistant.google.com/&quot;&gt;Google Assistant&lt;/a&gt; is interesting because it&amp;rsquo;s the culmination of years of work from the company to build the perfect ecosystem for knowing the right things about you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google knows what you&amp;rsquo;re doing, where you&amp;rsquo;re going, how you spend most of your time and what you&amp;rsquo;ll probably do next – just because you use its services every day. You might call that creepy, but I believe there&amp;rsquo;s a magic line where that&amp;rsquo;s actually incredibly useful and Google&amp;rsquo;s finally found it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Assistant can do things like pull up your agenda for the day, book you a table or, most importantly, know the difference between a question and you continuing the conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;videoWrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;1280&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/FPfQMVf4vwQ&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you ask Assistant &amp;ldquo;How long will it take to get from Downtown Chicago to home?&amp;rdquo; then follow up with &amp;ldquo;what restaurants are there?&amp;rdquo; it&amp;rsquo;ll know exactly what you&amp;rsquo;re talking about – a question that Siri would&amp;rsquo;ve fallen over on already.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Siri, by comparison to what Google showed today, looks like a glorified egg timer. Because Apple has chosen the route of absolute privacy, and can&amp;rsquo;t process any of your data or learn from it, the company remains in the dark about what you want, or when you&amp;rsquo;ll need it. Siri is, in effect, a toy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t misunderstand me here, Siri is an incredible innovation and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/2016/06/apples-differential-privacy-collecting-data/&quot;&gt;Apple has done some very interesting things&lt;/a&gt; to help it learn despite the restrictions it placed on itself, but the company is at a massive disadvantage: it&amp;rsquo;s flying blind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By putting Assistant in the home with the speaker, Google has taken it to the next level. Now you&amp;rsquo;re able to intimately interact with it on a daily basis, asking for simple information, receiving reminders about appointments or flights – directly pulled from your inbox by the way – without much effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/assist.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through learning about you, Google has built the ultimate way to actually build a useful, contextual search engine. There&amp;rsquo;s almost no comparison.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2016/09/01/apple-shows-off-the-first-siri-powered-apps-arriving-in-ios-10/&quot;&gt;Apple&amp;rsquo;s integration of apps into Siri is cute&lt;/a&gt;, and long overdue, but pales in comparison to the usefulness of having an entire search engine plugged in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google&amp;rsquo;s adaption of its Assistant inside its new messaging service &lt;a href=&quot;http://allo.google.com&quot;&gt;Allo&lt;/a&gt; is also intriguing: what if you could interact collaboratively with an AI-helper? To book a table, you&amp;rsquo;re able to ask Assistant for help, then discuss it amongst yourselves, then pull it back in to finish setting the appointment up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The experience is so magic you couldn&amp;rsquo;t dream of Apple pulling it off. iMessage works well enough, but Apple&amp;rsquo;s imagination – and speed – is nothing to be envious off. Siri in iMessage would be useful, if it could actually figure out what was going on in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Apple has focused on privacy as a selling point – and rightly so, given the battle it fought with the FBI – Google has taken the opposite approach, putting the data it has on you to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It risked that being perceived as creepy, for years, but I think it&amp;rsquo;s finally paid off with the manifestation of this Assistant that adjusts for your preferences, not just a boiler-plate voice assistant that acts the same for everyone else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that Google is officially playing in the hardware game, it&amp;rsquo;s going to be everywhere from your car to your house and that&amp;rsquo;s a big deal. Now its Assistant can be a persistent helper in your life, so for the first time, all those things it knows about is going to be put to work – and not for advertising.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>2016-10-04T00:00:00+02:00</pubDate>
          <link>http://char.gd/google/google-is-putting-apple-to-shame/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">http://char.gd/google/google-is-putting-apple-to-shame/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Welcome to the new Charged</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello and welcome to the new Charged website! It&amp;rsquo;s incredibly long overdue, and it&amp;rsquo;s finally here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the first in a series of upgrades to Charged – the biggest since I started writing the newsletter in 2014. Now we&amp;rsquo;re running the podcast, newsletter and a blog on the same platform making it much less confusing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tech underneath means it&amp;rsquo;s blazing-fast and you&amp;rsquo;re able to come to a single place to get everything. As this has grown beyond just a newsletter it was time to invest in modernizing everything, rather than just continuing to hack it all together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the near future we&amp;rsquo;ll be re-launching the newsletter format with a modern framework too, but in the meantime I&amp;rsquo;ll be blogging here more frequently and hope that this will become a place you refer back to so you can keep up with everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s kind of hard to believe that the tiny newsletter I started two years ago has grown to more than 9,000 subscribers and a podcast that&amp;rsquo;s had over 70,000 unique listens. Onward, to the next milestone!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for your support and continuing to read,
Owen&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>2016-09-25T00:00:00+02:00</pubDate>
          <link>http://char.gd/announcements/welcome-to-the-new-charged/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">http://char.gd/announcements/welcome-to-the-new-charged/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Google buying Twitter would be the best result for everyone</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Earlier today rumor broke that Twitter is engaged in talks with both Salesforce and Google for a possible acquisition of the social network, and the stock price went crazy, along with everyone on the platform itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People are complaining about the idea of Google owning Twitter, but here&amp;rsquo;s the thing: that&amp;rsquo;s actually one of the best possible exits for the company. Out of all the companies that could acquire Twitter, Google is absolutely the best one and Salesforce might be amongst the worst.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Much of the frustration about the idea of Google acquiring Twitter revolves around Google+, Buzz and the other failed attempts the search giant made at social media. Yes, they were all terrible, and yes Google still sucks – to date – at any and all social media, but that itself is what makes the company a great fit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google has learnt the hard way that design, money and forcing people to be a part of something are not a winning combination. It witnessed that first-hand as it grew Google+ and alienated both its diehard fans as well as everyone else – the company tried to force the network on us all by requiring sign-in using a social profile and it&amp;rsquo;s not about to make the same mistake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the thing: Google is not the same company it was in 2011 at all. Social media was new and the company had missed the boat, ultimately finding itself desperate for something to work in order to stay relevant as Twitter, Facebook and many others ran away with eye-watering active user counts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2016, Google finds itself with a new CEO, a better vision and improved focus. Sundar Pichai knows what he does and doesn&amp;rsquo;t want, and that&amp;rsquo;s been clear in his moves to date. Pichai hasn&amp;rsquo;t been afraid to cut services, double down on important programs and redirect resources to new ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing that Google under Pichai is ultimately missing? A newsfeed. Twitter is exactly that – and Google could easily acquire the social network and generally leave it alone, integrating its real-time feed into search and other products without annoying the core user base.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If Google integrated a Newsfeed product into Search for current events and related searches it would actually be a killer product for the company – and would lessen the need for direct monetization on Twitter itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately Google is the best suitor out of a bad bunch here – Salesforce almost certainly wants Twitter to turn it into a people-crunching CRM and you can bet the line behind the two waiting to acquire Twitter includes much more horrible companies too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On its own, Twitter is more dangerous to itself as a public company. It&amp;rsquo;s incredibly clear it&amp;rsquo;s not able to make rational decisions or even ones that benefit the user base, time and time again. A Google acquisition would bring the engineers, ad network and support the company needs to avoid going extinct.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>2016-09-25T00:00:00+02:00</pubDate>
          <link>http://char.gd/google/google-and-twitter-is-great/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">http://char.gd/google/google-and-twitter-is-great/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>iOS 10: the beginning of the end for apps as you know them</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Apple’s Worldwide Developer Conference is a rare chance to get a glimpse into how the company’s long-term thinking could reshape the app industry, as well as the web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although it’s probably said every year, it felt like this year’s WWDC was significant, even if a lot of people don’t realize it quite yet. To me, it signaled the beginning of the end of the way we use apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been playing with iOS 10 since the announcement, and in that short time it’s finally become clear how Apple plans to move its mobile platform into the future: by changing what it means to interact with apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With iOS 10, Apple wants to stop you from jumping in and out of apps all the time, instead encouraging quick dips into different services, without ever opening them entirely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rich notifications, which are part of iOS 10, let developers extend what a notification actually is in complex ways so you don’t actually need to open an app to reply, see a picture or get the latest news — a 3D touch on the notification reveals more information without leaving whatever you’re already doing. Tapping the home button takes you back to where you were.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a great example: I’m browsing Twitter, catching up on what my friends are talking about. I get a text from Femke, asking me if I want to go out for dinner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In iOS 9, I could have pulled down on the notification to reply, without the context of our previous messages, or I could have tapped on it to jump into the full Messages app and read the thread.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In iOS 10, you can 3D Touch a notification to open a popover window with full context, then reply instantly and go back to what you’re doing without ever breaking the flow of your previous task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s far less cognitive overhead because you’re not completely removing yourself from what you were doing before, so you’ll probably carry on once you’re finished replying rather than doing something else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Developers are able to do this with a huge range of different app types, giving you as a user new ways of accessing apps without ever really needing to open them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the same vein, widgets have been liberated from the notification center and appear front and center across iOS 10.
Now they’re on your lock screen, to the left of the home screen and in the 3D Touch menu of an app’s icon — giving you one less reason to actually open that app to get information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out this glimpse of an upcoming Ring smart doorbell widget, which lets you see live video and open the door instantly: no need to open the app, mess around with where to go and what to do: the options and information you need is right there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Need the weather? Swipe left on your lock screen.
Want to check your calendar? Just force touch on the app.
Keeping up with the game? Slide on over to Siri.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s most impressive about these changes is they’re also validation of a feature that felt a little lackluster before: 3D Touch — the hardware feature in the iPhone 6s which lets you push a little harder on the screen to view more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, 3D Touch is the ALT button like on your Mac. It lets you peek a little deeper inside apps and find out something interesting, rather than just right click them to get a menu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;iOS 10 is going to change the way we think about apps, because you won’t even need to open them most of the time.
Apps are suddenly less about performing tasks, and more about consuming, since whatever else that needs your attention can be done immediately without switching context to something else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the last year we’ve seen Facebook fighting to deeply integrate every app it possibly can into Messenger, like Uber, so you can order a ride without leaving a conversation. But what if that dead-simple idea of embedding services to be used where you are already could be extended to an entire phone? That’s what Apple just did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soon, you’ll be able to watch a YouTube video, while replying to your boss on Slack and iMessaging your friends — and it’s going to be a fundamental change to how all of us use the iPhone.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>2016-06-14T00:00:00+02:00</pubDate>
          <link>http://char.gd/apple/the-beginning-of-the-end-for-apps-as-you-know-them/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">http://char.gd/apple/the-beginning-of-the-end-for-apps-as-you-know-them/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Everyone’s wrong about Apple Watch. Here’s why.</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;With almost every new technology product comes a hype wave. Everyone will exclaim hyperbole about how great it is, then around 12–18 months later criticism creeps in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s part of the natural technology news cycle: get clicks for the shiny new thing, then get even more clicks for shitting all over it later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple’s products are some of the easiest targets for this, and Apple Watch seems to be going through it right now having just hit its one year anniversary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a selection of the latest headlines about the company’s year-old wearable:
My God-Awful Year With The Apple Watch
A year after its launch, it’s now clear that pretty much no one needs an Apple Watch
The Apple Watch, one year later: Did we expect too much?
The Apple Watch one year on: Why we’re frustrated by what could have been&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading these headlines you’d think Apple Watch was a piece of trash that basically everyone regrets buying — but I think it couldn’t be further from the truth for people actually wearing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For some, it’s changed their lives for the better, and I’m one of those people. I’ve been wearing mine for the better part of 10 months and still wear it daily, because it made subtle changes to the way I think that modified my lifestyle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I got my Apple Watch I was pretty sedentary, having just moved across the world to Amsterdam, I found myself having fallen out of an exercise routine, so I had no reason to move much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those annoyingly addictive three activity rings.
The first few weeks of wearing the watch were uneventful. Sure, notifications on my wrist are handy and the Dutch rain alerts so I would know when to head home to avoid getting wet were awesome, but what else was compelling here?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I grew accustomed to Apple Watch’s fitness nags, which constantly bother you to stand up or try for your goals, my attitude changed: I wanted to beat it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It became something of a personal obsession to beat those three exercise rings. I started going out of my way to achieve them every day — a little further on the bike home, or a quick walk around the block to get that last tiny chunk of calories into the red ring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around this time I started getting more attentive to my health — because I had become aware of it on a daily basis — and began considering running, so decided to try starting consistently in January.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to a combination of the Apple Watch running feature, and Runkeeper, it became another obsession to beat my own personal bests. I’m still trying to form better habits, but I’ve found myself running 10+ times a month — and just ran more than 8KM for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result, I’ve lost more than 10KG in about six months, after really getting stuck into the routine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, that’s a huge achievement, as I’d been trying and failing to stick with any plan to do that for years. The Apple Watch gave me a reason to fight, reminding me at every step of the way where I was at.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m more bullish on the Apple Watch than any of the company’s other products because it can have a material impact on the way I live my life. I’ve tried Fitbit, Android Wear and all the other ones I can think of, and they just don’t compare to how well Apple has tuned the balance of useful information and alerts to get you moving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the Apple Watch reviews have addressed problems the device has, like slow apps or that it supposedly doesn’t have a killer use case yet, but I’m living proof that the Apple Watch has a day one killer app:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can change your life in material ways, just by helping you make tiny behavior tweaks. All I needed was a push to get moving, and it delivered it — it might be all you need too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tiny rings that haunt my waking hours&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be it through notifications making me more aware of my actual surroundings because I don’t have to pull out my phone, that I stand up whenever the thing nags me to, or that it actually makes me want to go for a run, my Apple Watch quickly became a life-aid I can’t take off anymore during the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t get me wrong, there are plenty of things that a second-gen Apple Watch can improve on — I recommend most people wait until the next one now because it looks like an upgrade is on the horizon — but long-term I’ll be putting it on every single day, because it’s more than enough right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For all the complaints in the media about Apple Watch, there are hundreds of people who’s lives are changing in meaningful ways that you aren’t hearing about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m one of them, and I’m glad to have worn this fancy wrist computer so far, because it’s one of the few gadgets that intimately changed my life rather than just get in the way of it all the time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>2016-05-24T00:00:00+02:00</pubDate>
          <link>http://char.gd/apple/everyone-is-wrong-about-apple-watch/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">http://char.gd/apple/everyone-is-wrong-about-apple-watch/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>