<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Charged</title>
    <description>The best tech news distilled</description>
    <link>http://char.gd</link>
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Charged newsletter is back – with its biggest overhaul ever</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I took a big break over the last two months to take a look at Charged newsletter, the state of things and where we could go next. It ended up being a two month long break, but it was well overdue - for over two years I&amp;rsquo;ve been sending it every weekend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stepping back was good, and gave me time to reflect on things. When I started out, I thought I might get 100-200 subscribers, but today we&amp;rsquo;ve grown to 11,000 active subscribers, which was totally unexpected! As a result, I haven&amp;rsquo;t had time to look after the newsletter (let alone this site) until recently, so it got a bit stale, and even didn&amp;rsquo;t work in places.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, &lt;a href=&quot;http://charged1.createsend.com/t/ViewEmailArchive/i/DD00A51F026183B0/C67FD2F38AC4859C/&quot;&gt;Charged newsletter is back, and it&amp;rsquo;s better than ever&lt;/a&gt;. For the first time in two years I&amp;rsquo;ve built the entire newsletter from the ground up &lt;a href=&quot;http://foundation.zurb.com/emails.html&quot;&gt;using a framework called Ink&lt;/a&gt; that means you don&amp;rsquo;t have to use the old-school HTML that email traditionally demands. That means it&amp;rsquo;s far more maintainable, and works in almost all email clients – even Outlook 2007!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;img style=&quot;max-width: 50%; margin-left:0px; margin-bottom: 15px;&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/charged_mobile.png&quot;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a more modern design, that finally matches this website, a cleaner layout, and proper email client support, Charged is better than ever! I&amp;rsquo;m planning to share more in-depth analysis of single stories both in the newsletter and here, as well as dive even deeper in the podcast, which is out every week too!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On top of that, the newsletter archives will all finally be hosted here in the next week, in a single place, rather than being across the various platforms I&amp;rsquo;ve used over the years, like MailChimp and Campaign Monitor – dive into all 100+ newsletters &lt;a href=&quot;http://char.gd/archive&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://chargedpodcast.com&quot;&gt;podcast&lt;/a&gt;, which is now 34 episodes in, has had more than 150,000 unique listeners in just six months. John Edgar and I discuss technology each week, and it&amp;rsquo;s been a blast so far, as well as one hell of a learning process. We started out with crappy audio and poor editing, and as we&amp;rsquo;ve learnt we&amp;rsquo;ve perfected the sound, our own discussions and the overall product – I hope you love it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alongside the podcast late last year we launched an invite-only Slack community for discussing topics, meeting people and talking with us directly, which has been a success as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More than 400 people use the Slack every week, and discussions have blossomed on everything from politics to technology&amp;rsquo;s impact on the world. Later this year I&amp;rsquo;m planning to offer community accesss, a daily newsletter and private updates for a small monthly fee to help continue the creation of Charged, and I&amp;rsquo;ll have more to share on that soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you enjoy the new design, and if you have any thoughts, feedback or ideas for the future, I&amp;rsquo;d love to hear from you! Just hit reply on any of our emails (or comment here).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>2017-01-22T00:00:00+01:00</pubDate>
          <link>http://char.gd/announcements/We-are-back-big-time/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">http://char.gd/announcements/We-are-back-big-time/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Taking a quick nap</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a copy of the email I sent out to subscribers in late November. Charged newsletter will be back – really soon – but I wanted to take a break to reflect, rebuild and make sure it&amp;rsquo;s better than ever.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hey there, and happy Thanksgiving!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve been around for a while you&amp;rsquo;ll know what Charged newsletter has been a thing for over two years at this point. Over that time I&amp;rsquo;ve sent more than 100 newsletters and more than 10,000 of you have joined the community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been an incredible journey, since I mostly had just expected a few people to sign up to my silly side project, and it&amp;rsquo;s grown bigger than I ever expected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because I&amp;rsquo;m sending this every week - and recording the podcast - I haven&amp;rsquo;t had the time I wanted to dedicate to make this newletter better or up to the standard I&amp;rsquo;d expect for myself. A few weeks ago we launched new Charged branding for both the newsletter and podcast, but it did&amp;rsquo;t make it here yet – and it&amp;rsquo;s long overdue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, for the next few weeks the newsletter is going to take a break to reassess where we&amp;rsquo;re at, and to rebuild the template to be properly responsive, and in line with our new style. It&amp;rsquo;ll definitely come back, but it&amp;rsquo;ll look very different, work properly and be much easier to read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want a sneak peek? Here&amp;rsquo;s what we&amp;rsquo;re working on:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/ipad-newsletter.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to chat about anything feel free to just reply to this email! I&amp;rsquo;d love to hear from you – otherwise, enjoy the podcast in the meantime, until this comes back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks so much for subscribing, and reading this newsletter. It means a lot - and it&amp;rsquo;s incredible to me that the community has grown so much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See you soon,&lt;br&gt;
Owen&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>2016-12-04T00:00:00+01:00</pubDate>
          <link>http://char.gd/announcements/We-are-taking-a-nap/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">http://char.gd/announcements/We-are-taking-a-nap/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>I got a Google Home and finally understand the future of computing</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;For decades the technology industry has been chasing the holy grail of computing: natural language conversation. Humans have always wanted to talk with computers like a real person, but for a long time, it’s felt like a pipe dream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Research has stretched decades. IBM had a computer that could understand spoken words as early as the 1970s, but it took more than an hour to crunch a single sentence. Dragon Dictate, the first consumer voice product, launched in 1990 for more than $9,000 per license.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, just two decades later, you have a voice assistant in your pocket that can understand you pretty damn well for essentially no cost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s incredible to think about, but shackling these incredible voice assistants to phones meant while they had come leaps and bounds into the future, have mostly been restricted to doing menial tasks and being used for stupid jokes.
When Google announced its Siri competitor, Google Assistant, last month I wrote that it looked more promising than Apple’s version ever had, but it’s further ahead than I thought. I picked up a Google Home while I was in New York last month and it’s changed the entire way I think about voice, and how computers can actually help us in a natural way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I always thought Siri was cute, but mostly dumb. It’s easy to stump it by simply asking it a vague question, or following up a query like “what movie is Jennifer Lawrence in” with “how old is she?” The illusion quickly falls apart, and as far as I’ve seen, Siri isn’t much use outside of being an egg timer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Naturally, given this I was skeptical — but having watched the Google Home launch video and seen all the hype about Amazon Echo, I decided to give it a go and see if it’s as magic as promised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/gh-2.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google Home is… well, a fairly simple device if you start looking closely. It’s a speaker with two far-field microphones that essentially services as a place in the physical world for Google Assistant to live — that’s pretty much it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can speak from anywhere in a room and ask a question or perform an action, play a game or even control your home. As far as I can tell, the moment you say “OK Google” it starts streaming your voice to the cloud for processing, and stops the moment you’re done — almost no processing is done on-device, and otherwise it’s mostly a glorified Chromecast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interacting with Google Home is awesome however. It’s super quick, and entirely conversational. Once you ask a query like “OK Google, how do I say let’s play video games and hang out in Japanese” it’ll reply, out loud within milliseconds “ビデオゲームをプレイしてみましょう.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The beauty of the device is really in how it’s able to understand both context and the seemingly bizarre, however. If you say “OK Google, who’s that guy who plays God in lots of movies” it’ll say “Morgan Freeman.” From then, if you ask “what else is he known for” it’ll pick up that you’re still referring to Morgan Freeman, and tell you a bunch of stuff from his biography.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My favorite command is a simple one: “how’s my day looking?” Home spouts off the things in my calendar, the weather in Amsterdam, how long my cycle to the office will take and then jumps into a two-minute world news briefing. It’s simple, but actually really addictive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Home really comes into its own if you buy a whole bunch of smart devices, too. I reluctantly picked up a set of Philips Hue smart light bulbs, and wired up my smart thermostat to the device with IFTTT. Now when it’s cold, I can just say “OK Google, turn up the heat” and it does adjusts up a few notches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even better, “OK Google, goodnight” turns off all the lights, stops the music, turns off the TV and lowers the heat automatically. If you have a few Chromecast devices it’s nifty too — then you can just say “Play Carly Rae Jepsen in the Living Room” and it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;also it gets super cutesy if you ask to play a game &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/MouOPqc541&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/MouOPqc541&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Owen 💁 (@ow) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ow/status/800748993739390976&quot;&gt;November 21, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;script async src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s quite amazing how powerful the microphones are, and you really feel like you’re talking to a human. The magic of that seamlessness is quite powerful. So much so, in fact, that it’s actually a little creepy interacting with Home on its own the first few times — it’s fast enough that your brain really thinks it’s just talking to a person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s the magic that Google’s pulled off here, and it’s really compelling. Home has a lot of personality, and if you ask a particular question that deserves a different tone of voice, to emulate enthusiasm or being reserved, it actually reacts how you’d expect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ask to play a game, and Google Home says in a higher-pitched, faster-paced voice “Oh boy, this is gonna be so much fun!” The Wall Street Journal reported that Google has hired Pixar writers to give the device more personality, and it constantly shines through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/gh-bench.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some obvious gaping holes for improvement: Home, ridiculously, doesn’t work properly with Google Apps accounts, so I can’t get my work calendar with it. It also can’t connect with multiple people’s calendars, so my partner doesn’t have her own information in it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of all, I don’t like saying “OK Google” constantly, and I wish the company would let me name it — but I suspect it’s set this way so it can consistently learn millions of times what it’s hearing to get a big data set.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One other weird thing is occasionally you just stump it entirely with searches that work in other Google products. Ask “what movies are on near me” and it’ll get confused: “sorry, I really didn’t understand what you meant by that.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m sure it’ll get better over time, but even small improvements in these areas will help a lot. It seems like a massive oversight that Home can’t handle multiple people in a house… since that’s one of the most obvious use cases — bizarre.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought Home would be a gimmick, but a few weeks after launch and we’re using it all day at home for music, news and lots of other stuff. It feels like a glimpse of the future, and for the first time I’m really convinced voice assistants could take off. Google Home truly makes Siri look like a toy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Home is one of my favorite purchases of the year — you won’t regret it if you’re interested in dipping your toes in the smart home world, and it’s of such a high standard that it feels like Google is playing in Apple’s league for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything ‘just works’ and you feel like you’ve got a Star Trek-style communicator everywhere in your home. If it keeps getting better, I can say for sure that I want one of these in every room of my home — we’re really living in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post was &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/charged-tech/i-got-a-google-home-and-finally-understand-the-future-of-computing-e7de00487d7d#.go6jycreh&quot;&gt;originally published on Medium&lt;/a&gt; - thanks for reading &amp;lt;3&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>2016-12-02T00:00:00+01:00</pubDate>
          <link>http://char.gd/home/i-got-a-google-home/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">http://char.gd/home/i-got-a-google-home/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Apple just told the world it has no idea who the Mac is for</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Last night’s Apple event was bizarre — I had been anticipating this show for a while, mostly looking forward to being able to stop telling people not to buy a Mac, because everything was so outdated. But, even though what I saw was interesting, it really feels like Apple has lost its way.
It’s strange — there’s nothing actually wrong with what Apple announced: USB-C on the Mac is great, a thinner, more powerful machine is intriguing and, while it’s too early to say, the Touch Bar could possibly be a gimmick, but it could be useful for helping people discover what shortcuts exist as they use the computer
.
The thing is, I can’t figure out who this is for other than those who are on really old machines. Myself, and everyone else, seems to be wondering what, exactly, is the selling point of this upgrade. I have a MacBook Pro 15&amp;quot; from 2013 and it’s still going strong and the majority of the time it’s plugged into a large display for creative work, coding or whatever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Touch Bar is a great example of this. First, it feels like an excuse to not just add touch to the Mac in the first place. While Microsoft is busy letting you touch the entire display, Apple’s making you look down at your keyboard to interact instead — bizarre.
But the “Pro” in Apple’s devices isn’t even accurate anymore. It used to be the best notebook on the market for creatives, developers and people with big requirements. One look at this slide shows Apple has no idea exactly where its demographic lies:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/mb1.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Do you want the Pro, the Pro or the Pro? Which one is for Pros? I’m confused.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The MacBook Air is dead, which is great news, but why are there two MacBook Pro 13&amp;quot; now? The only difference is one doesn’t have the touch strip, but why not just… call it the new MacBook air to alleviate confusion?
Adding an additional option, without the touch bar was a smart move. I was speaking with a number of friends on Slack during the event, who all said they’d buy the new Mac if you could get it with a normal function row. Then, Apple dropped this and they were interested. But as a final “fuck you” for those that get this, it has two less ports, slower memory and a worse GPU– and to add them back it’s basically the same price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The fact that Apple itself considered the MacBook Pro as a competitor to the MacBook Air shows it’s not really a Pro.” 
-@lapcatsoftware&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What video editors are going to do edits on a tiny touch bar below the screen? What DJ — like Apple demonstrated — wants to use a tiny touch bar to mix their music when the action is… on their screen?
The event also left Apple with a ton of bizarre loose ends. At the iPhone event in September, Apple told the world that headphone jacks were dead because wireless headphones are superior — so why is there a headphone jack on the Mac? Even worse, Apple has delayed its wireless headphones which were supposed to change the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From there, the questions just get even more ridiculous:
Why can’t you plug the Lightning headphones that come in the iPhone box into the new Mac? Why doesn’t the iPhone come with the right cable for the new MacBook Pro? Why doesn’t Apple make a screen that properly works with its own devices? Why did Apple highlight how great the Touch Bar is for Messaging, but didn’t even port most of the new iMessage features to macOS properly? Do I have to carry two pairs of headphones now? How do I charge my Lightning cable mouse? Why remove the HDMI port, a standard that’s still incredibly popular for plugging into TVs? Why remove the SD card, a popular slot for… creatives using cameras?
“Watching someone DJ with the top of a keyboard was just embarrassing, doubly so from the company that makes the iPad and as recently as this year’s WWDC showed off its ability to be used by blind people.”
Even worse, what took so long to get to this point? Many people have been waiting a year or more for a refresh, and this itself wasn’t even that notable.
The new MacBook Pro has a Skylake chip, not the Kaby Lake one that’s recently landed– if you look at benchmarks at the top-end it’s pretty clear something is wrong: the CPU in this MacBook Pro actually appears to perform worse than the older one.
CNET spoke to Apple’s marketing head, Phil Schiller, who said:
Marketing chief Phil Schiller, software engineering lead Craig Federighi and top designer Jony Ive explained, in exclusive interviews earlier this week, why the Mac matters. Since they say it’s so important to Apple, we asked them why it took four years, four months and 16 days to deliver what they call a “milestone” and a “big step forward” for its top-of-the-line laptops.
“The calendar isn’t what drives any of the decisions,” Schiller says in a 90-minute briefing at Apple’s headquarters in Cupertino, California. “We challenge the teams to do great work and sometimes that great work can be done in one year, sometimes it takes three years… What we really care about is creating new innovations in the Mac and continuing the story that has really defined Apple for so many years.”
What does that even mean? It took four years to add a touch bar to the keyboard, which delayed any meaningful progress in the meantime? Apple’s customers are those that need powerful machines, but it delayed them infinitely for what amounts to a vanity project that the core demographic of Apple’s customers probably won’t even use.
This does, indeed, speak to the longevity of the machines that Apple sells: you can use a MacBook from 2012 right now and probably can’t tell the difference. But therein lies the problem — the company waited four years, then didn’t really deliver any real future-value other than it’s “new.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The size of the MacBook is perhaps the most compelling component.
The other perplexing component of the event was the sheer lack of anything interesting for existing Mac owners. No new accessories — how cool would a Bluetooth version of the Touch Bar be — and no desktop computers.
Now you’ve got an aging iMac with old ports, a very out of date Mac Pro and a bunch of weird old accessories that haven’t been touched in years — oh and about a million dongles anytime you want to plug something in.
“I think if you’re looking at a PC, why would you buy a PC anymore? No really, why would you buy one?”
– Tim Cook, talking about the iPad Pro
The good news is there’s finally a modern Mac available, even if there are some small compromises, I just hope that Apple keeps up the pace from here on out. For the last 12–24 months it’s been painful explaining to someone that Apple will surely update its machines soon.
To be clear, USB-C is a good thing. Someone has to do it, and jump in the deep end — but the way Apple has done it by forcing you into a corner to deal with it yourself rather than making it an easy transition… and you don’t even get the full power cable in the box anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Courage (via Twitter)
For a company that prides itself on ecosystem, and thinking of the ‘end to end’ experience, Apple has utterly lost its way.
Yesterday, the world got an iteration on something the company’s been doing all along, rather than something that’s a vision for the future.
Apple spent the entire event comparing itself to its own past, rather than showing us the future, and even then painted a very clear picture: it has no idea who the Mac is for.
Peter Kirn wrote last night that it was hard to watch the Apple event:
Apple’s obsessive naval gazing in the Mac event today speaks volumes. This is a company with no real vision for what its most creative users actually do with their most advanced machines. So, instead, they look into the past.
The Mac made its name because it embraced the creative industry where Microsoft missed the boat, but in 2016, it seems like it’s going to miss out on the next wave entirely: the updated Mac isn’t suitable for the heavy graphics, virtual reality or 3D work it’s so famous for being good at.
Is the new MacBook a mildly-interesting upgrade to the old one? Yes! Would I get it if I was in the market? Probably. But, to be frank, there’s simply no reason to right now if you already own a Mac that works well, and for the first time I’d at least consider looking somewhere else before buying it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple, it seems, is angling for the ‘amateur creative’ and isn’t interested in anything else anymore. It wants the market that sits in coffee shops with its brand and only buys Apple, but doesn’t mind so much if the core demographic disappears. Maybe that’s OK — there’s probably good money in it — but it’s a real shame.
When the 12&amp;quot; MacBook was released, I thought it was pretty forward-looking. Apple had produced a machine that was both impossibly small, had a number of interesting new concepts — and even took the “courage” to drop all ports for a single USB-C port: a bold move. It’s not a perfect machine, but it’s a look at a world where you can have a whole computer in your bag and not even notice it.
To me, the event last night was Apple trying to remind the world it cares about the Mac, but more than anything else the undertone was this: Apple only cares about the Mac when it’s convenient, but even then, it’s obviously not thinking that hard about the impact is has.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>2016-11-01T00:00:00+01:00</pubDate>
          <link>http://char.gd/macbook/apple-just-told-the-world-it-has-no-idea-who-the-macbook-is-for/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">http://char.gd/macbook/apple-just-told-the-world-it-has-no-idea-who-the-macbook-is-for/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>The reason I keep going back to Apple might surprise you</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the last few months I&amp;rsquo;ve complained a lot about what Apple is doing – some of the moves it&amp;rsquo;s making have been frustrating, like dropping the headphone jack, the lack of any progress on OS X and in general how poor iCloud is. The media loves to portray Apple as always right, but as a customer, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t always feel that way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started considering switching from the iPhone and Apple Watch to something else, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theverge.com/2016/10/7/13207382/google-pixel-xl-camera-photography-samples&quot;&gt;like Google&amp;rsquo;s interesting new Pixel phone&lt;/a&gt;, especially with that amazing camera. But today, I had a realization about why I stick with Apple&amp;rsquo;s products: the customer experience really is a class above everyone else in the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had an iPhone 6s essentially since it came out, but recently it started developing some strange issues. First, the loudspeaker became distorted so you couldn&amp;rsquo;t clearly hear anything at all. Annoying, but not the end of the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, after iOS 10 came out, I noticed my battery life went off a cliff. Not slightly-less-but-managable, but instead needing to hang off a charger because I&amp;rsquo;d lose 25% just opening Slack for a few minutes. It was pretty bad, and I blamed software at first, but realized something else might be going wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I booked a Genius appointment, like I have many times before, to see if something was really wrong. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the appointment, I described the problem and we ran through a series of diagnostics on the phone automatically. It was, conclusively, screwed – the speaker alone warranted an entire replacement, but the battery issues were caused by a logic board problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple replaced it on the spot. No questions, accusation, argument or begging, I just got a new phone five minutes after walking in. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/proof.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s amazing how this experience flies in the face of every other type of customer service interaction we&amp;rsquo;re used to. Usually, when something goes wrong your default setting is to go in expecting a fight, or at least resistance to your problem. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously, it&amp;rsquo;s probably your fault, and retailers love to point that out. If they finally admit fault, they&amp;rsquo;ll usually send it off for repairs rather than actually just give you a new one or fix it on the spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In that world, Apple is starkly the opposite. Something&amp;rsquo;s wrong? Great, here&amp;rsquo;s a better phone for free. Broken screen? Perfect, it&amp;rsquo;ll be fixed within an hour for a nominal fee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The entire Genius system is so good, that I realized this level of service is the major reason I&amp;rsquo;m still buying Apple products: I know if something goes wrong with my MacBook, iPhone or Watch, that I&amp;rsquo;ll be taken care of, and nobody&amp;rsquo;s going to accuse me of doing something wrong or make me suffer because of the issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had this experience consistently with Apple&amp;rsquo;s customer care, who are happy to just help you get going again, rather than run you around, and it&amp;rsquo;s refreshing. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No other phone maker, carrier or even laptop maker does this, and it&amp;rsquo;s easy to forget that while we&amp;rsquo;re distracted about whether or not the iPhone 7 is the best phone ever – I just don&amp;rsquo;t care anymore, as long as I know I can actually get help when I need it. With the Pixel, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.androidpolice.com/2016/10/04/googles-247-live-support-for-the-pixel-phones-comes-complete-with-screen-sharing/&quot;&gt;Google seems to be trying&lt;/a&gt;, but time will tell whether that actually matters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, your reaction to this post might be &amp;ldquo;oh, but Apple&amp;rsquo;s products are overpriced&amp;rdquo; but when I&amp;rsquo;ve factored in that I&amp;rsquo;ve received four full phone replacements over the years as well as a Mac replacement, no questions asked, it&amp;rsquo;s worth every dollar. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That peace of mind, and great service, is worth whatever premium you might think is attached to the company&amp;rsquo;s products. Being treated like a human, rather than just another complaining asshole, is refreshing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of Apple&amp;rsquo;s product decisions are frustrating, yes, but I&amp;rsquo;ll be a loyal customer long-term, provided Apple&amp;rsquo;s stores and support systems continue to exist. Nobody else can offer that level of service, nor have they come close thus far. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>2016-10-04T00:00:00+02:00</pubDate>
          <link>http://char.gd/iphone/the-reason-i-keep-going-back-to-apple/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">http://char.gd/iphone/the-reason-i-keep-going-back-to-apple/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Google's software is putting Apple to shame</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;The narrative of Apple vs Google has always been a persistent one: Apple is great at hardware and software that fits together perfectly, and Google was never particularly good at either of those.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, Google held a &amp;ldquo;Pixel&amp;rdquo; event to unveil its new self-designed and self-built hardware: a phone, a router and, most intriguingly, a home assistant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The home assistant, &lt;a href=&quot;https://madeby.google.com/home/&quot;&gt;aptly named &amp;lsquo;Google Home&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a&gt; is a small speaker that lives in your house and can respond – from basically anywhere – to any question you might have for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/ghome.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That new speaker is powered by a piece of software called Google Assistant. It&amp;rsquo;s the company&amp;rsquo;s first push into what it calls &amp;#39;personalized search&amp;rsquo; – or a Google that knows about you intimately and can help based on the context it has from your email, search habits or any other data it has access to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://assistant.google.com/&quot;&gt;Google Assistant&lt;/a&gt; is interesting because it&amp;rsquo;s the culmination of years of work from the company to build the perfect ecosystem for knowing the right things about you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google knows what you&amp;rsquo;re doing, where you&amp;rsquo;re going, how you spend most of your time and what you&amp;rsquo;ll probably do next – just because you use its services every day. You might call that creepy, but I believe there&amp;rsquo;s a magic line where that&amp;rsquo;s actually incredibly useful and Google&amp;rsquo;s finally found it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Assistant can do things like pull up your agenda for the day, book you a table or, most importantly, know the difference between a question and you continuing the conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;videoWrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;1280&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/FPfQMVf4vwQ&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you ask Assistant &amp;ldquo;How long will it take to get from Downtown Chicago to home?&amp;rdquo; then follow up with &amp;ldquo;what restaurants are there?&amp;rdquo; it&amp;rsquo;ll know exactly what you&amp;rsquo;re talking about – a question that Siri would&amp;rsquo;ve fallen over on already.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Siri, by comparison to what Google showed today, looks like a glorified egg timer. Because Apple has chosen the route of absolute privacy, and can&amp;rsquo;t process any of your data or learn from it, the company remains in the dark about what you want, or when you&amp;rsquo;ll need it. Siri is, in effect, a toy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t misunderstand me here, Siri is an incredible innovation and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/2016/06/apples-differential-privacy-collecting-data/&quot;&gt;Apple has done some very interesting things&lt;/a&gt; to help it learn despite the restrictions it placed on itself, but the company is at a massive disadvantage: it&amp;rsquo;s flying blind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By putting Assistant in the home with the speaker, Google has taken it to the next level. Now you&amp;rsquo;re able to intimately interact with it on a daily basis, asking for simple information, receiving reminders about appointments or flights – directly pulled from your inbox by the way – without much effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/assist.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through learning about you, Google has built the ultimate way to actually build a useful, contextual search engine. There&amp;rsquo;s almost no comparison.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2016/09/01/apple-shows-off-the-first-siri-powered-apps-arriving-in-ios-10/&quot;&gt;Apple&amp;rsquo;s integration of apps into Siri is cute&lt;/a&gt;, and long overdue, but pales in comparison to the usefulness of having an entire search engine plugged in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google&amp;rsquo;s adaption of its Assistant inside its new messaging service &lt;a href=&quot;http://allo.google.com&quot;&gt;Allo&lt;/a&gt; is also intriguing: what if you could interact collaboratively with an AI-helper? To book a table, you&amp;rsquo;re able to ask Assistant for help, then discuss it amongst yourselves, then pull it back in to finish setting the appointment up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The experience is so magic you couldn&amp;rsquo;t dream of Apple pulling it off. iMessage works well enough, but Apple&amp;rsquo;s imagination – and speed – is nothing to be envious off. Siri in iMessage would be useful, if it could actually figure out what was going on in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Apple has focused on privacy as a selling point – and rightly so, given the battle it fought with the FBI – Google has taken the opposite approach, putting the data it has on you to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It risked that being perceived as creepy, for years, but I think it&amp;rsquo;s finally paid off with the manifestation of this Assistant that adjusts for your preferences, not just a boiler-plate voice assistant that acts the same for everyone else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that Google is officially playing in the hardware game, it&amp;rsquo;s going to be everywhere from your car to your house and that&amp;rsquo;s a big deal. Now its Assistant can be a persistent helper in your life, so for the first time, all those things it knows about is going to be put to work – and not for advertising.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>2016-10-04T00:00:00+02:00</pubDate>
          <link>http://char.gd/google/google-is-putting-apple-to-shame/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">http://char.gd/google/google-is-putting-apple-to-shame/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Welcome to the new Charged</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello and welcome to the new Charged website! It&amp;rsquo;s incredibly long overdue, and it&amp;rsquo;s finally here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the first in a series of upgrades to Charged – the biggest since I started writing the newsletter in 2014. Now we&amp;rsquo;re running the podcast, newsletter and a blog on the same platform making it much less confusing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tech underneath means it&amp;rsquo;s blazing-fast and you&amp;rsquo;re able to come to a single place to get everything. As this has grown beyond just a newsletter it was time to invest in modernizing everything, rather than just continuing to hack it all together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the near future we&amp;rsquo;ll be re-launching the newsletter format with a modern framework too, but in the meantime I&amp;rsquo;ll be blogging here more frequently and hope that this will become a place you refer back to so you can keep up with everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s kind of hard to believe that the tiny newsletter I started two years ago has grown to more than 9,000 subscribers and a podcast that&amp;rsquo;s had over 70,000 unique listens. Onward, to the next milestone!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for your support and continuing to read,
Owen&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>2016-09-25T00:00:00+02:00</pubDate>
          <link>http://char.gd/announcements/welcome-to-the-new-charged/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">http://char.gd/announcements/welcome-to-the-new-charged/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Google buying Twitter would be the best result for everyone</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Earlier today rumor broke that Twitter is engaged in talks with both Salesforce and Google for a possible acquisition of the social network, and the stock price went crazy, along with everyone on the platform itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People are complaining about the idea of Google owning Twitter, but here&amp;rsquo;s the thing: that&amp;rsquo;s actually one of the best possible exits for the company. Out of all the companies that could acquire Twitter, Google is absolutely the best one and Salesforce might be amongst the worst.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Much of the frustration about the idea of Google acquiring Twitter revolves around Google+, Buzz and the other failed attempts the search giant made at social media. Yes, they were all terrible, and yes Google still sucks – to date – at any and all social media, but that itself is what makes the company a great fit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google has learnt the hard way that design, money and forcing people to be a part of something are not a winning combination. It witnessed that first-hand as it grew Google+ and alienated both its diehard fans as well as everyone else – the company tried to force the network on us all by requiring sign-in using a social profile and it&amp;rsquo;s not about to make the same mistake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the thing: Google is not the same company it was in 2011 at all. Social media was new and the company had missed the boat, ultimately finding itself desperate for something to work in order to stay relevant as Twitter, Facebook and many others ran away with eye-watering active user counts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2016, Google finds itself with a new CEO, a better vision and improved focus. Sundar Pichai knows what he does and doesn&amp;rsquo;t want, and that&amp;rsquo;s been clear in his moves to date. Pichai hasn&amp;rsquo;t been afraid to cut services, double down on important programs and redirect resources to new ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing that Google under Pichai is ultimately missing? A newsfeed. Twitter is exactly that – and Google could easily acquire the social network and generally leave it alone, integrating its real-time feed into search and other products without annoying the core user base.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If Google integrated a Newsfeed product into Search for current events and related searches it would actually be a killer product for the company – and would lessen the need for direct monetization on Twitter itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately Google is the best suitor out of a bad bunch here – Salesforce almost certainly wants Twitter to turn it into a people-crunching CRM and you can bet the line behind the two waiting to acquire Twitter includes much more horrible companies too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On its own, Twitter is more dangerous to itself as a public company. It&amp;rsquo;s incredibly clear it&amp;rsquo;s not able to make rational decisions or even ones that benefit the user base, time and time again. A Google acquisition would bring the engineers, ad network and support the company needs to avoid going extinct.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>2016-09-25T00:00:00+02:00</pubDate>
          <link>http://char.gd/google/google-and-twitter-is-great/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">http://char.gd/google/google-and-twitter-is-great/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>iOS 10: the beginning of the end for apps as you know them</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Apple’s Worldwide Developer Conference is a rare chance to get a glimpse into how the company’s long-term thinking could reshape the app industry, as well as the web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although it’s probably said every year, it felt like this year’s WWDC was significant, even if a lot of people don’t realize it quite yet. To me, it signaled the beginning of the end of the way we use apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been playing with iOS 10 since the announcement, and in that short time it’s finally become clear how Apple plans to move its mobile platform into the future: by changing what it means to interact with apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With iOS 10, Apple wants to stop you from jumping in and out of apps all the time, instead encouraging quick dips into different services, without ever opening them entirely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rich notifications, which are part of iOS 10, let developers extend what a notification actually is in complex ways so you don’t actually need to open an app to reply, see a picture or get the latest news — a 3D touch on the notification reveals more information without leaving whatever you’re already doing. Tapping the home button takes you back to where you were.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a great example: I’m browsing Twitter, catching up on what my friends are talking about. I get a text from Femke, asking me if I want to go out for dinner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In iOS 9, I could have pulled down on the notification to reply, without the context of our previous messages, or I could have tapped on it to jump into the full Messages app and read the thread.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In iOS 10, you can 3D Touch a notification to open a popover window with full context, then reply instantly and go back to what you’re doing without ever breaking the flow of your previous task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s far less cognitive overhead because you’re not completely removing yourself from what you were doing before, so you’ll probably carry on once you’re finished replying rather than doing something else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Developers are able to do this with a huge range of different app types, giving you as a user new ways of accessing apps without ever really needing to open them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the same vein, widgets have been liberated from the notification center and appear front and center across iOS 10.
Now they’re on your lock screen, to the left of the home screen and in the 3D Touch menu of an app’s icon — giving you one less reason to actually open that app to get information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out this glimpse of an upcoming Ring smart doorbell widget, which lets you see live video and open the door instantly: no need to open the app, mess around with where to go and what to do: the options and information you need is right there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Need the weather? Swipe left on your lock screen.
Want to check your calendar? Just force touch on the app.
Keeping up with the game? Slide on over to Siri.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s most impressive about these changes is they’re also validation of a feature that felt a little lackluster before: 3D Touch — the hardware feature in the iPhone 6s which lets you push a little harder on the screen to view more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, 3D Touch is the ALT button like on your Mac. It lets you peek a little deeper inside apps and find out something interesting, rather than just right click them to get a menu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;iOS 10 is going to change the way we think about apps, because you won’t even need to open them most of the time.
Apps are suddenly less about performing tasks, and more about consuming, since whatever else that needs your attention can be done immediately without switching context to something else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the last year we’ve seen Facebook fighting to deeply integrate every app it possibly can into Messenger, like Uber, so you can order a ride without leaving a conversation. But what if that dead-simple idea of embedding services to be used where you are already could be extended to an entire phone? That’s what Apple just did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soon, you’ll be able to watch a YouTube video, while replying to your boss on Slack and iMessaging your friends — and it’s going to be a fundamental change to how all of us use the iPhone.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>2016-06-14T00:00:00+02:00</pubDate>
          <link>http://char.gd/apple/the-beginning-of-the-end-for-apps-as-you-know-them/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">http://char.gd/apple/the-beginning-of-the-end-for-apps-as-you-know-them/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Everyone’s wrong about Apple Watch. Here’s why.</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;With almost every new technology product comes a hype wave. Everyone will exclaim hyperbole about how great it is, then around 12–18 months later criticism creeps in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s part of the natural technology news cycle: get clicks for the shiny new thing, then get even more clicks for shitting all over it later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple’s products are some of the easiest targets for this, and Apple Watch seems to be going through it right now having just hit its one year anniversary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a selection of the latest headlines about the company’s year-old wearable:
My God-Awful Year With The Apple Watch
A year after its launch, it’s now clear that pretty much no one needs an Apple Watch
The Apple Watch, one year later: Did we expect too much?
The Apple Watch one year on: Why we’re frustrated by what could have been&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading these headlines you’d think Apple Watch was a piece of trash that basically everyone regrets buying — but I think it couldn’t be further from the truth for people actually wearing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For some, it’s changed their lives for the better, and I’m one of those people. I’ve been wearing mine for the better part of 10 months and still wear it daily, because it made subtle changes to the way I think that modified my lifestyle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I got my Apple Watch I was pretty sedentary, having just moved across the world to Amsterdam, I found myself having fallen out of an exercise routine, so I had no reason to move much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those annoyingly addictive three activity rings.
The first few weeks of wearing the watch were uneventful. Sure, notifications on my wrist are handy and the Dutch rain alerts so I would know when to head home to avoid getting wet were awesome, but what else was compelling here?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I grew accustomed to Apple Watch’s fitness nags, which constantly bother you to stand up or try for your goals, my attitude changed: I wanted to beat it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It became something of a personal obsession to beat those three exercise rings. I started going out of my way to achieve them every day — a little further on the bike home, or a quick walk around the block to get that last tiny chunk of calories into the red ring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around this time I started getting more attentive to my health — because I had become aware of it on a daily basis — and began considering running, so decided to try starting consistently in January.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to a combination of the Apple Watch running feature, and Runkeeper, it became another obsession to beat my own personal bests. I’m still trying to form better habits, but I’ve found myself running 10+ times a month — and just ran more than 8KM for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result, I’ve lost more than 10KG in about six months, after really getting stuck into the routine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, that’s a huge achievement, as I’d been trying and failing to stick with any plan to do that for years. The Apple Watch gave me a reason to fight, reminding me at every step of the way where I was at.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m more bullish on the Apple Watch than any of the company’s other products because it can have a material impact on the way I live my life. I’ve tried Fitbit, Android Wear and all the other ones I can think of, and they just don’t compare to how well Apple has tuned the balance of useful information and alerts to get you moving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the Apple Watch reviews have addressed problems the device has, like slow apps or that it supposedly doesn’t have a killer use case yet, but I’m living proof that the Apple Watch has a day one killer app:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can change your life in material ways, just by helping you make tiny behavior tweaks. All I needed was a push to get moving, and it delivered it — it might be all you need too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tiny rings that haunt my waking hours&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be it through notifications making me more aware of my actual surroundings because I don’t have to pull out my phone, that I stand up whenever the thing nags me to, or that it actually makes me want to go for a run, my Apple Watch quickly became a life-aid I can’t take off anymore during the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t get me wrong, there are plenty of things that a second-gen Apple Watch can improve on — I recommend most people wait until the next one now because it looks like an upgrade is on the horizon — but long-term I’ll be putting it on every single day, because it’s more than enough right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For all the complaints in the media about Apple Watch, there are hundreds of people who’s lives are changing in meaningful ways that you aren’t hearing about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m one of them, and I’m glad to have worn this fancy wrist computer so far, because it’s one of the few gadgets that intimately changed my life rather than just get in the way of it all the time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>2016-05-24T00:00:00+02:00</pubDate>
          <link>http://char.gd/apple/everyone-is-wrong-about-apple-watch/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">http://char.gd/apple/everyone-is-wrong-about-apple-watch/</guid>
        </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>